so welcome back to this another lesson
and in this lesson we are going to look
at web logic concept in the previous
lesson I give you a high-level brief
overview of what topics we are going to
cover in this lesson so or in this
module so let's start with the first and
the most important about WebLogic
concept so what is a web logic server
it's nothing but an application server
which is Java EE 7 version of Java
compliant so application server is the
server on which you deploy the
application that has logic and this
application server helps you to run that
application running on the application
server so that's what is the WebLogic
server provide so what you do you deploy
or run and distribute Java based
applications on this application server
this application server access other
services like database to store the data
or messaging server to to send the
messages across between applications or
to connect to the external enterprise
systems like ebusiness suite or three
bill or peoplesoft or maybe salesforce
or s AP and shown so these that is the
WebLogic server WebLogic server various
exactly is used it's used pretty much
every Oracle product beeps ooh or Oh BAE
access manager Identity Manager
ebusiness suite Fusion Applications
Enterprise Manager 13c and so on so
you'll understand and appreciate if
you're looking for cloud Java cloud
services Sewer cloud services a
directory cloud service play from and
most of the pretty much swap cloud
service integration cloud service on
some platform you might have access to
the WebLogic some you may not have but
all underlying feeding using WebLogic
server now in 12c version there's a it
supports multi-tenancy which means what
do we what is multi-tenancy we'll cover
that in in a minute in the sub in the
respective lesson we have a dedicated
lesson for this so where one domain is
supporting multiple
what is tenant what is the domain we'll
look that in a minute
now WebLogic server now is also
supported on a docker container and if
you're big now if you don't know what is
it docker build may be worth googling
what is it docker solution
it's basically quickly and rapidly
deploy applications on and on a plate
form which is called a docker plate form
which is a additional software think of
it as a like a virtualization or virtual
server but it's not actually the virtual
server it's it's an in in compact
application in a docker container so Web
projects support that as well and other
competitors the lot of application
servers out in the market but these
three are top ones apache followed by
web logic and then IBM websphere these
are the three main players in
applications of a space you will see
either a patch a tomcat
you will either see IBM WebSphere or
Oracle WebLogic server there are plenty
more but these are more the most common
implementations of application server so
this is all about WebLogic server in
terms of if you look at the task
what a administrator does administrator
install the rom logic server they
configure domain they also you or a web
logic administrator will be deploying
the application given by the developers
you manage and migrate the domain from a
test environment to the product moment
integrate with identity access
management systems security system
third-party systems or like databases or
a business feed and so on troubleshoot
any issues find out the puff missed unit
some app users might say hey it's
running slow so that's where you look at
Java Virtual Machine garbage collections
or the struct threads and we'll cover
all these things on a high level in
coming lesson then monitor and manage
the WebLogic server configure and set up
high availability in disaster recovery
so these are all tasks of logic admin
and let's quickly look at what are the
tools available to you come handy so
there is a tool
WebLogic admin console we'll see and in
a minute about WebLogic console how does
it look like so it's a graphical user
interface to manage the entire domain
you another graphical user interface
which is Fusion Middleware control then
you have a command-line utility which is
called a web logic scripting tool or W
LST you also have restful api is exposed
by the WebLogic server through which you
can manage and deploy applications
you also have configuration wizard that
will be used to create or extend a
WebLogic domain
we'll see all these things in coming
lesson you also have Apache and
deployment tool which is from open
source to deploy applications on top of
a logic server
you also have SNMP agent which is a
simple network management or protocol to
and through which web logic has been
exposed you can you can do the hooks and
manage WebLogic server so these are
various tools on available for web logic
so in the next lesson we are going to
look at our head on to where we talk
about another most important component
or or concept which is called as
WebLogic domain but before we go to
WebLogic domain before we head on to the
next lesson let's quickly recap on what
we covered in this in this lesson so we
looked we started with the WebLogic
server I said it's an application server
it uses to run the applications and you
deploy application on top of that int
will see it supported multi-tenancy what
that multi-tenancy will we have going to
discuss in a minute
it also can be run or web logic can be
run in a docker based containers or
docker containers and other competitors
are IBM WebSphere and Apache Tomcat the
admin tasks these are some of the admin
tasks done by member logic
administrators you also have the tools
handy which are two graphical user
interfaces FM logic scripting tool
restful api is configuration with the
end and SNMP agent so head on to the
next lesson we will look at what exactly
is a admin server what is ever bloody
domain what is cluster what are the
resources and services and where are
these configurations store
I'll see you in next lesson