hi good morning in this presentation or
session we are going to show you how to
install Oracle WebLogic server there are
three parts or three steps you do in
order to install Oracle WebLogic server
in part one you install JDK or Java
development kit which will be used to
run your WebLogic server the next part
is you create you install oracle
weblogic server and third parties you
configure or you create WebLogic domain
and start your project server the first
step is installation of Oracle JDK so
I'm going to a staging directory where I
have JDK downloaded which is stage
Oracle JDK so if you notice here I have
two JDK software one is rpm file and
second a star file so you can either log
in as root and run this RPM when you run
this RPM and is going to install your
JDK under user java jdk 1.7 dot 51 so
this is jdk 1.7 update 51 so if you go
inside bin directory you will see I've
already installed JDK using RPM and c
java version 1.7 update 51 so one method
is you install RPM or using RPM - ivh
and the file name or RPM name other
method is you simply enter the JDK 7 the
way we are I'm going to show you again
here which is let's go back to trade ek
Oracle stage JDK and now on tau star
minus x VF jdk update 9 Linux 64-bit are
so it's unzipping the file now in under
folder jdk 1.7 and if i so this is my
jelly key home or you install jdk if i
go to the bin directory and then Java -
version I see Jenny give 1.7 update 9 so
to repeat when you install Oracle
WebLogic server first part you need to
do is you know to install JDK and there
are two ways to install JDK one is
installing install using rpm and second
is you simply enter the tar file into
the directory in which you would like to
install your jdk so i'm going to pick
the first method which is installation
using RPM which have already done in the
past using on my my jdk software
location a's user java jdk this is my
java home and inside that these the
files I have if I could have pinned and
I can run the Java version to check what
my Jake jdk server version is which is
1.7 update 51 in next step I'm going to
show you how to install Oracle WebLogic
server are in third step we are going to
create WebLogic server domain