welcome back to this another lesson and
in this lesson we will look at WebLogic
server installation and that's where the
real hands-on will start so we are
actually going to install the WebLogic
server so first of all there are two
type of installation in WebLogic server
you can either do a typical install or a
custom install and this is a screenshot
from an 11g our screens might differ
slightly between 11g and per se so right
now what I am Telling unless I specified
it's for 11g version of the blodgett now
as at the time of recording these videos
which is apparently 2018 the latest
version is 12c we are covering both 11g
as well as 2lc because lot of customers
are still on 11g lot of Fusion
Middleware customers are still on 11g of
logic so you can either install typical
which will install most of the component
or you can do a custom install and when
you select custom stall you can choose
which components you want to install
then if you're doing Fusion Middleware
installation like if you're doing it for
so ah Oh BIA web central access manager
identity manager and so on you typically
need to select or you select one with
coherence so when you download WebLogic
WebLogic comes a standalone route logic
or verb logic with coherence so make
sure you select web logic with covenants
and coherence is nothing but a data T of
layer which you will leverage the data
that you pull from the database you
store on the application tier under
coherence layer so this is too typical
to installation if you're doing custom
install you select cursor install and
you choose the component that you want
so you can pick up and then remove
things that you do not want as I said
earlier
coherence is mandatory if you're doing
for Fusion Middleware protect now so
that was about what kind of installation
type you can get then in which mode you
can install you can install you either
using graphical user interface or using
interactive both graphical user
interface or command line
so either interactive or graphical user
interface so so graphical user interface
is available both on
for Windows and for Linux or you can
also use console in console is again
interactive like graphical but it's a
text-based this is no GUI or graphical
user interface it's console it's a
text-based again available in both
Windows and Linux
so what you do all you do you say - mode
is equal to console then you can also do
a silent install and silent is non
interactive it's only available from a
package installer so what you do you say
- mode is equal to silent and then you
say silent underscore XML and then you
give path of the XML file now in 20 the
step is or the option or the parameter
for silent XML file is slightly
different or you have a response file in
11g so it will see this is I'm talking
about 11g you have an XML file in 12c
it's a response file the option is
slightly different but you have all
three more into LC and 11g the command
might be slightly different so you have
a graphical which is interactive and GUI
based
you have a console which is interactive
and text-based silent which is non
interactive which means you provide all
the details that you need to that logic
expect like a middle way home or
WebLogic home or whatever component to
select or way to install should we
automatically download patches from
Oracle or not all these you already
provided in an XML file and then you
pass this XML file with the installation
that's called as self install so how you
do silently store again we have a step
by step activity guide covered for you
so make sure wherever you're watching
this under that area you should have a
step by step activity guide so you pre
the XML file with the entry like this so
what it's saying
so some parameter some settings you can
change in this so you say select and say
oh this is my BA home which is my middle
way home this is the directory in which
I am going to install my WebLogic server
these are components or products I'm
selecting core components I'm selecting
this is my way of mine Java Virtual
Machine or JVM is installed this is my
node manager port number and and so on
so this is all about
the XML file that you select then use
silent install and you provide the XML
file path in as an option so some of the
good things which you must know so make
sure if you're installing any UNIX avoid
don't do it from root user and do it
from non root user maybe create a user
like Oracle or some other user then if
you are installing the WebLogic server
for fusion middleware product I only
said you need coherence and why you need
coherence because some or a lot of
fusion will middleware product uses
coherence for cluster communication so
like things like sois or oracle access
manager some components use coherence so
other thing to remember is very
installing you install WebLogic and you
install fusion will be a component make
sure you install using same user both
these components now the logic when you
install it expect jdk to be already
installed and make sure the JDK version
you are using or planning to use is
certified with the WebLogic server and
there's a certification metric that
comes if you can't find it reach of the
support drop an email to supported key
Tony Academy comm team will help you
depending on which version of the logic
you want or you can google it and you
will see that and such for Oracle
WebLogic server tells your 11g or
whatever words in you're looking for
certification metrics then by default
when WebLogic server installs it unzips
the entire SAR file into a temporary
area and then install from there and
create a staging area in under tamp now
sometimes you may not have enough temp
or the temp might be used by a
permission might not be usually you
should have all the right permission but
sometimes that same file might be
written by or not enough space so during
the station you can provide an option
like - D Java dot IO dot TMP di a-- and
you can specify any other temporary file
so that it's rather than using forward
slash then it's good to use some other
location so that's all about WebLogic
overview now in the next lesson be able
to look at how to install and configure
WebLogic server 12c let's look go and
quickly wrap up this lesson would be
so we looked at installation types we
looked at typical and custom then we
looked at custom installation in that
installation mode which is graphical
console and silent and in silent used to
create XML file and pass on this file we
also looked at good things to know now I
will see you next lesson will be look at
how to install and configure WebLogic
server 12c i'll see you in next lesson