welcome back to this another lesson in
Oracle Fusion Middleware training and if
you're listening it at some other place
it's part of Oracle WebLogic server so
in this we are looking at domain room
and in this lesson be able to focus on
domain home earlier I mentioned about a
high level overview of domain and domain
whom is the top-level directory in which
you have domain specific directories so
things like admin server directory Java
database configuration JMS configuration
files the log files and everything we
discussed briefly in module 1 about
various homes and domain home was one of
them so when does this to mean home gets
created domain whom gets created when
you configure a WebLogic domain how do
you configure everyone you do mean you
configure it when you run config dot
asset you will see in this module how do
you run or create a membership domain
but domain whom contains top-level
directory in which you have all the
files and this is what you see in the
right hand side and that's a example or
or server where we have already
installed or files some look like so
this is still here this is my aura based
home or base domain or this is my domain
home inside that I have a bin folder
which is we been here
so bin folder will have all the
start-stop commands my servers folder
will have my admin and manage servers my
node manager folder will have node
manager depending on this impotency you
can decide and have node manager here or
some other place as well so if I go
under servers folder I will see a admin
server currently there's only admin
server started so these servers will get
created a folder servers will get
created when you start the server's
first time so I've only started admin
server in this domain and hence you see
admin folder within admin folder or
within the server folder I have cached
data data log and security we'll cover
that in a minute later then you have
config folder within domain whom the
config folder will have configuration
this config file folder I said earlier
that config dot XML this will have all
the configuration for entire domain you
can open this configuration
I'll tell what all things are configured
in this domain
you also have within config folder you
have GD BC folder and in JDBC folder you
have the Java database connectivity
final configuration file for the
database connectivity we'll see that in
a minute the bin folder will have all
the start-stop so you have start
WebLogic got SH to start the admin
server you have stopped WebLogic that sh
to stop the WebLogic server then you
have similarly start instead of node
managers start and stop the manage
servers as well so we will see all these
things what all our start/stop admin
server and manage servers or node
manager so this is all about a domain
home then I said there is a server and I
told you that there are two type of
servers admin server and manage server
we'll go a little bit deep into what
this administer our manage servers are
and how does they look like so this is a
screenshot about from a graphical user
interface which I call Oracle WebLogic
administration console of a logic
console and once you configure the
domain and once you start the admin
server you will be able to login and
access this console we are going to
cover that in a minute
or in subsequent lessons so when you
login on left hand side you explain this
and mom and you see servers and under
servers you see right hand side there's
something called as admin server and
other servers rest all are called as
manage servers so and means our first
one and only and the manage servers so
that's about servers so what is server
server of two type which is nothing but
1 is of admin server and just all our
manage servers these servers are used to
host the applications and resources like
what web archive er enterprise archive
czar Java archive JDBC to connect to the
database JMS to message exchange between
applications so that for application now
each server will have its own JVM and
JVM stands for Java Virtual Machine
I repeat JVM stands for Java Virtual
Machine the Java Virtual Machine will
have some memory beginning memory in
which the code is being executed Java
code is being executed then it is a new
concept in 12c which is
dynamic servers servers which are
automatically being spent or spawn or
created automatically based on the
configuration as the load increases you
can automatically scale up the services
in 12c we'll see that in dynamic servers
in a minute so this is how the geo
virtual machine looked like so I said
it's nothing but a Java Virtual Machine
this is how the Java Virtual Machine
looked like what do you see you do PS
minus EF and grep for Java on the UNIX
machine so if I'm doing connecting to
the server and I say PS and then us and
then pipe and then grab minus I and Java
and if I run that command I is going to
give me if my Java processes are running
it's going to give me some output and
here I get output so what it's saying
it's saying oh this is a JDK I'm using
or Java development kit 1.7 it's a
server it's starting with memory X and s
means small memory footprint one gig it
can grow up to two gig and name of this
web server is over m and score server
and there are some other properties of
this server so the JVM is this
particular process which is running
under the process ID two six eight nine
nine is the java virtual machine in
which the code is going to be executed
so this is about a java virtual machine
each server which either admin server a
managed server and on node - server will
have its own JVM
they will have its own memory sizes they
will have its own pump size and max pump
size again we'll cover that when these
pump size and maximum size are covered
in the blonic so if you're part of the
project weenie this should be somewhere
in the craning if you're listening this
in the project you should see high
performance tuning and that's when we
have trouble to cover Java Virtual
Machine in detail we'll go deep into
that how do you tools what tools you
used to tune that java virtual machine
how do you find out the garbage
collection and everything so that's
about java virtual machine so as i said
head on to the next lesson we'll look at
and good deep into this admin server in
- server and we'll also look at how
admin server in - ever talk to each
other and
what is something called as managed
service independence or MSI mode and
we'll also look at clusters and dynamic
clusters which are introduced into NZ so
handle to the next lesson but for now
let me do a quick recap on this I said a
domain whom or domain is nothing but or
domain whom gets created when you
configure a domain and it has top-level
directory in which you have all the
other configuration files or log files
or start-stop files so that's a domain
you your servers which are of admin
server and a managed server the servers
each server represents a Java Virtual
Machine these servers where you host
water file efi jar file JDBC JMS each
server have its own JVM and there's a
new concept in 20 which is called as
dynamic servers and what exactly is
admin server
what is the managed server what is
cluster how do admin server talk to -
server how what is - or independence and
so on let's head on to the next lesson
so I'll see you in next lesson