so welcome back to this another lesson
and in this lesson we are going a little
bit deep into admin and manage servers
earlier we looked at obvious I said
there is a server of to type admin and
manage servers we took we have it
briefly touched on Java Virtual Machine
or JVM and now let's look at what is
admin server so admin server in a domain
there can be only one and always one
admin server and there is a one-to-one
relationship between domain and admin
server the admin server will always be
tied to that domain so admin server is a
server that is used to manage a domain
if you need to make any modifications it
is done through admin server so if you
need to manage any resources or other
servers like manage servers that all
done through admin server and if
configuration changes will done through
admin server so admin server is always
tied to the same many servers admin
server can across domains
similarly each domain can only have one
admin server and it can't connect to any
other admin server it can only connect
to its own admin server a domain can
only connect to its own admin server so
it's used to manage a domain it there
will be only one and only one admin
server
it's a singleton service which means you
can't run it in active active cluster
like we do in manage server will go deep
into this clustering and single done
service when we look at high
availability for now as if it's a single
internal service which means it can run
on at any given point in time on only on
one server you can migrate from one
server to another server however only
active at any one point in one server
other might be down out passive it can
only spend or manage one domain and
technically you can deploy a service on
top of our application on top of it
admin server but it's highly recommended
not to deploy in product production or
in normal deployment of void deploying
application on top of admin server
because it's a singleton service also
the primary purpose of this admin server
is to start or host the management part
then you have a managed server it's
similar to admin server but the role of
managed server is to run the
applications or host applications you
can have 0 to n minus servers then it's
independent to other servers other
servers or other manage servers unless
they are part of cluster which means
they can run independent to each other
other servers they can talk they can
independently run manage servers with
independent to other manage servers and
applications are deployed so let's
suppose you deploying a so application
or obiee application or Identity Manager
application access manager application
or for that reason Oracle management
server for DBS or or any fusion
applications they will be deployed and
running its own manage servers so how
admin and manage servers are related to
each other
so what happens is admin server will
have all the configurations however
managed server will also maintain a
replica of that sub configuration in its
own repository so each managed server
will have a local copy which it pulls
out down from the admin server and every
time it starts and for some reason if it
can't access the admin server at the
start of the managed server it will use
its local copy which means only for the
first time in the life cycle so when you
create a managed server after that when
you start only that time first time the
admin server should be up and running
because it needs to collect or retrieve
all the files from the admin server and
store it in so own local repository so
that's called as first time only for for
starting of manage servers the admin
server should be up and running after
that it will use if admin server is not
up and after it start up admin server
can go down and manage server will
continue to run its own on its own it
doesn't need an admin server after the
startup and later also if you let's
suppose you shut down and in admin
server is not available next time you
can still next time you can start it
means a many server without an admin
server
and that is called as managed server
independence or MSI mode in blahblah
jerk MSI where a managed server can be
managed or started independent to the
admin server so let's suppose you've
started the admins a managed server
without an admin server and some
configurations of chains with the admin
server which many server is not yet
aware of and then what I will happen the
minute you start the admin server admin
server will again push those changes
onto the managed server if it's related
to add manage server or next time cycle
of manage server manager will pull these
changes from the admin server so this is
called as manage server independence so
just to do a quick recap you have an
admin server you have a managed server
and admin server is for administration
purpose managed server is where the
applications are learned
then the managed server and admits of
are related to each of them they talk to
each other through a concept called or a
utility called node manager for starting
stopping only guys I repeat I starting
stopping that - only from console so
I'll pop that while I'll cover those
things in little bit later however admin
server can talk directly to the managed
server and but many server can also
manage itself without an admin server
after after once first time startup
however you wouldn't be able to make any
changes you can start stop and run the
application on top of a managed server
independent to the admin server it even
if while running let's suppose if you
have so application which is deployed in
many server admin server goes down only
you won't be able to change the
configuration you won't be able to come
change any configuration however your
users will continue to run your their
applications there will be no impact on
the end users because managed server is
still enough up and running
that's called as - our independence mode
so headed to the next lesson we will
look at clusters in 11g and new feature
or infancy which is called as dynamic
clusters which is used for elasticity or
automatic upscaling of servers will also
look at dynamic clusters server
templates
and data sources in the next lessons
hydral to the next lesson way we cover
clusters and dynamic clusters and
dynamic servers in WebLogic 12c as well
as some component in 11g so i'll see you
in next lesson