so welcome back to this another lesson
and in this lesson we are going to look
at clusters and dynamic cluster briefly
in the previous lesson we looked at
servers will be looked at admin server
and managed server so let's look at what
does cluster represents so cluster is
nothing but a logical collection of or
collection or group of servers running
simultaneously and working together and
acting as a single or or acting as a one
server from a clients point of view I
repeat one more time cluster is nothing
but a collection of servers running as a
single unit from a client point of view
and which has more or less similar
configuration and similar applications
deployed so that if one much managed
server goes down another managed server
in the cluster can transparently
failover or sessions data from one
server to another and and for client a
they will never notice what happened or
if anything failed so cluster will help
in high availability or also in
scalability so let's suppose you have a
lot of load on a one application you can
put that application into cluster with
multiple servers all acting as one
single unit from a client point of view
for scalability or high availability so
so so server is nothing but a collection
of servers or cluster is nothing but
collection of servers running
simultaneously and acting as a single
unit from client point of view so you
can make changes to a cluster or a
member of a cluster by saying change
this configuration and say update this
configuration on all the cluster member
so either let's suppose you want to
deploy an application on a managed
server so rather than deploying on a
individual many servers you say deploy
on the cluster and all the members that
are part of that cluster will have that
application deployed so that's another
property of cluster so cluster is
nothing but collection of
- or more - servers technically you can
have a cluster with one - server only
but you might have more many servers but
having one cluster with one - server
doesn't give you benefit of high
availability or scalability but
technically even clerkly the cluster
with one managed service only so the
cluster members which are nothing but a
manage servers they can be on the same
machine or different machines and
there's a cluster communication which
could be unicast and multicast we'll see
that what is unicast and multicast when
we look at a high availability in its
dedicated module we'll see this cluster
communication we'll see the differences
between these two so that's cluster so
what you see in the diagram on the right
hand side is nothing but you have a
admin server which is on left hand side
and you have 4 on top and 4 on bottom
you have cluster 1 and cluster shows in
this domain you have one admin server
you have 8 manage servers for many
servers in cluster 1 and 4 - servers in
cluster - and the members within cluster
can can talk to each other using either
something called as unicast or multicast
the way the disputes so that's a cluster
then in Qin see there's a new concept
called dynamic cluster and dynamic
cluster is nothing but a cluster that
contains one or more dynamic servers I
repeat it's only in 12c it's not
available in 11g integration 12c dynamic
cluster is nothing but a cluster that
has one or more dynamic servers that
bring to the point what is dynamic
server we'll cover that in a minute
so in a dynamic cluster the servers are
scaled up automatically as the
application demands so I repeat the
servers in a dynamic cluster will
automatically scale up or add themselves
so that means when you're defining a
dynamic cluster you are saying this is
my minimum number of servers and it can
grow up to 12 15 18 20 many servers so
if your application requires right now -
it will be - if
your application later has load
increases you can those members or their
servers in the cluster in a dynamic
cluster can automatically increase based
on the configuration in the Newton so
that means it needs a port number it
needs some default mechanism to identify
what port number to run what JVM size to
run what name we should keep all those
things we can do so dynamic clusters
that's a property of dynamic cluster it
uses something called a server template
to create the dynamic servers so
template is nothing but a layer or or or
or a set of configurations that used to
create a dynamic server and dynamic
servers come or dynamic couple of
dynamic servers will make a cluster or a
dynamic cluster so server template uses
defines a configuration that will be
used when we create a dynamic server so
this is one example of that so you
that's a dynamic cluster so I didn't say
you creating a cluster from a bridging
console and you see you with a do and a
static cluster which is first and second
option right inside on the circle which
is dynamic cluster when you create the
dynamic cluster you will get a screen
like on one on the left hand side that
says what is the size of the dynamic
cluster size between two servers right
now it can grow up to eight service or
what is the name of the manager we will
say dynamic cluster zero one and then -
and it will say one two three four or
name
so that's name of the manage servers or
dynamic servers in the cluster then
dynamic servers are nothing but a
servers that gets created by using the
server template by dynamic cluster so
dynamic cluster will tell based on the
load will dictate hit create a more -
more many servers but out of type
dynamic which using a template which
will automatically may be created and
what do you see you could if the
application can create or the domain can
create automatically or you as an
administrator can go and create these
dynamic servers but they'll be using a
template or
our template so what what do you see in
the console have already created a
dynamic cluster and that in the dynamic
cluster we created a two servers or
dynamic servers so cluster when you
create a cluster and when you define it
at that time it will create these
dynamic servers so what you see type
dynamic that means there is a these
there in this domain there as one admin
server in to many servers and these two
more many servers are dynamic servers
created by a dynamic cluster and then
you have a server template I said
earlier just now that for this dynamic
service to be created it needs a
template from using Mita to create this
dynamic servers so templates are nothing
but it enables to define a common
non-default attribute which means oh
what should be the name so in this case
if the previous example if you take the
known the non default attribute in this
case is prefix server name prefix which
is dynamic cluster 0 1 - it will dictate
that this is how so it enables to define
a common non-default attribute which
could be 0 1 0 2 0 3 0 4 and so on then
server templates are used to create the
dynamic clusters the members in the
dynamic cluster will be using or dynamic
cluster will be using a server template
to create a dynamic server and you can
create your own templates by using going
to the WebLogic console and the clusters
you can say server template and you can
create new template if you don't create
any template it will otherwise use the
default template in order to create
these dynamic servers so that's all
about the servers clusters we'll look at
the other topics like GD b c and j ms g
DB c stands for Java database
connectivity if an application needs to
talk to the database it will use JDBC
and there are three different type of
JDBC generate griddling and multi data
source we will see that and JMS in the
next lesson so let me do it quickly cap
in this lesson we looked at the cluster
which is nothing but collection of two
or more servers on which you have an
application deployed on both the servers
and from time point of view they are
acting as a single unit
cluster numbers can be a different host
or same host and they communicate of
members in the cluster communicate to
each other using something called as
either a unicast or multicast what are
these be able to look at in high
availability then there's a dynamic
cluster which is nothing but clustered
that gets created that have members
automatically grow or shrink based on
the load and those members are called as
dynamic servers because they are
dynamically created by the dynamic
cluster and they use or being created
using a server template and you can
define your own server template so
that's about clusters in this let's
handle to the next way we look at GD BC
and Jamie's I'll see you in next lesson