so welcome back to this another lesson
in module WebLogic server and in this
lesson we are going to look at node
manager and machine but before I tell
road manager machine quickly what we did
in previous lesson was data source and
we looked at JMS and now let's look at
node manager so node manager is nothing
but a java process running on each host
or a machine where WebLogic server is
running so I repeat one more time node
manager is a Java process which is
running or which usually run on a server
where WebLogic admin or manage servers
or any type of web logic servers are
running what node manager helps known
manager helps in remotely or in in help
in enabling or works for or helps in
starting or stopping services remotely
and services I mean is the server's
managed server or admin server and for
some reason if server crashes abnormally
node manager if it started by node
manager then get go and restart that
server again it must be always if you
want a server to be started using the
logic console or through web logic
scripting tool then node manager must be
always running there are different ways
to start the services we will see that
when we look at the start and stop and
one of them is using start WebLogic dot
SH or start manage WebLogic dot SH which
is shell scripts or you can also start
them from a manage servers you can start
them from a graphical console which is
WebLogic admins web ready console or you
can also start them both admin server as
well as manage server from the blodgett
scripting tool and if you have to do
that using the basic scripting tool then
or from a web logic console then node
manager must be running and it's only
used to manage and maintain configure
maintain or the server life cycle to
start and stop services
so having said that you can run your
servers without node manager as well so
you can have node manager all down and
you can run servers independently
without any need of node manager
similarly let's suppose you have started
a server using a node manager which is
why a logic controller WebLogic
scripting tool and then your new manager
goes down your server will still
continue to run now the way you deployed
newton manager you can have multiple
deployment topology you can have one
node manager associated with multiple
domains in a sir on on that physical
host I repeat one more time you can have
one node manager serving multiple
different domains which means node
manager is not specific to or not a part
of just any domain node manager can be
associated with multiple domains on a
host or you can deploy it in a way
saying each domain will have one node
manager so it's all down to what you
feel comfortable with and that's what
you can set up so if I know so what you
see in the diagram let's suppose I have
a two machines let's suppose two
different machines and the yellow
represents into a man is a node manager
and the red represents a admin server
now I have one more machine which is on
the right-hand side where you have where
you have a manís server which is
currently down which is represented by
got it now dotted line and you want to
start that managed server which is
represented by the dotted line on the
upper of our image so what you're going
to do you are going to tell your going
to issue a command from the WebLogic
console and say go and start the server
- server where this managed server is
deployed and sitting on another machine
so they'll be association of managed
server with a node manager let me repeat
one more time will be association of a
manager work with a node manager and the
association happens by the Machine the
see in the next slide so note admin
server will see that this node manager
is running or associated with which
machine and on that machine what what
node manager is configured so admin
server will issue a command to the node
manager node manager will then in turn
go and start this managed server and
that's how this process works so let me
first let's see first of all where this
configuration are on the server or what
are the associated configurations with
respect to the node manager so I'm
currently so the node manager by default
for 11g I am going to focus only on 11g
and then picking up to NC is simple and
12c slightly there is a slight change in
the way node manager is configured or
done but the concept remains same so the
the configuration for node manager will
be all the configuration file log file
everything will be under the logic
server home under the directory or file
called servers and in that you will have
bin folder and you have a script called
start node manager dot SH and that will
start other node manager there's no
script to stop the node manager you have
to kill in order to stop the new manager
process in 11g princey there is a script
but I will focus on 11 GS n so in 11g
there is no process or there's no script
to stop the node manager you have to
kill it once you have started the loan
manager all the configurations and
everything will be under the common
folder so you go under M but common not
common Oracle home it's under WebLogic
home common folder and within common
folder you will go into the node manager
folder and here you will have all the
files like node manager log files or
anything any errors everything will be
going to node manager dot log file
they'll be a node manager dot properties
file so when the node method starts it
will use this node manager properties
dot file to start the node manager and
you can change this file here node
manager does properties file so it will
tell what where is my domain file what
all domains are associated with this
node manager it will be given in this
fight
where's my java home what is the lesson
address for this this node manager
what is the listen port for this node
manager and it's blank which means it is
running on all the IP addresses
configured on this machine
what is the listen port and so on so we
come out of this file here and then the
node manager dot property domain file
will have what all domains are
associated with this node manager so we
will see here and say this one domain
which is the the base domain and this is
the location of this domain that is how
you see or you can figure it or you
start it now as I said earlier there
will be association with the machine and
I am going to tell you machine in a
minute but let's first go and try to
start a server in the WebLogic console
through a web logic console so I have a
server called for example sua server and
I go and try to start this server I will
say control and I'll select the sua
server and say start and the minute I
start the server it says the so server
does not have a machine associated with
this and what is the machine which is we
can configure it from here I'll come
I'll go and explain the now front
presentation so machine is nothing but
it identifies a physical host on which
the server is running that server could
be an admin server or that server could
be a managed server so machine is used
to associate a WebLogic server with the
host on which that that managed server
admin server runs it is used by the node
manager to start if a server or restart
a failed server it's also used by
cluster or or or in a scenario where the
serve the session information needs to
be replicated in selecting the closest
cluster member to replicate that session
again be able to cover that in high
availability a module will be good deep
dive into this cluster communication but
if node manager is up and if the
services are started using new manager
it will be used in that scenario
so what happens so what how I do or what
I go here is I can create a machine on
which I want to start the sewer server
and then associate this managed server
through this machine so I'll go and to
server here and I'll create a machine
called new machine so I take a control
called lock and edit and say new machine
and I can give this name this machine
any name of my choice it's just a
virtual or or a logical representation
of the actual machine on which I want to
start this server so I will say it's 0 1
and say it's off a type UNIX machine
because I know it's a Linux or UNIX
machine which is 1 or 2 IP now this is
what I was saying is that each machine
will have a Associated node manager so
now this is the node manager properties
how the node manager is running so by
default node manager can run in SSL as
are SH plain SSL leave it to default SSL
and I say on which machine this node
manager I want or machine to be
associated and I want to associate this
machine then appropriate node manager on
which this node manager is running so
I'll say 192 dot 168 I want to run it on
the same machine so a 1 + 1 0 - I could
have done localhost as well save and say
finish now this machine should be
associated to the manage server that I
want to start so I'll go to servers I'll
say so a server and I say now this is
associated with this so a 1 and save it
and I activate the changes which means
now if let it save so now if I want to
start the sua server the so our server
admin server will check where this - a -
server is way is is running or which
machine this is associated with with
this and if you go to that machine or my
admin server will go to that machine and
see what is the node manager associated
with that so in this machine are at node
manager and say so that means admin
server has to
send a command to this node manager with
listening on this machine on this port
and say hey go and start is to a server
and that's how this is going to work so
let's suppose if I go and start the
service on so and I try to start and see
a and say it start now this time I'm not
getting that error which I got earlier
saying hey there's no machine associated
because now we have associated a machine
here so I'll say yes started
however it's saying a request has been
sent to start the selected server
which means the request has gone that
means when that looks like the managed
server or the node manager is running
that's why a brick quest has gone so
otherwise if node - is down you will see
another error saying the node manager is
not available or down so if you see here
now I saw associated leave right now on
14th of April just few minutes ago and
it has sent a command to issue or it has
started or issued a command to start the
show underscore server 1 which means now
it has started or issued the command
this is how the machine or node manager
and machines are associated within a
domain so let me do a quick recap on
this so node manage is nothing but a
java process and if want to see the
process now if you want to see the
process you simply see and say PS - Kiev
and fight and grep for - I and node
manager and node manager and so this is
my node manager process which says it's
using this JDK it's starting with 32 MB
mmm and it can go up to 200 MB if
required and this is WebLogic node node
manager and so it's nothing but a java
process which is used to remotely start
and stop in managed server or services
or also restart a failed server services
can run without a node manager but if
you won't as I said earlier to be
started using a remotely WebLogic
scripting tool or console then node
manager is required machine is nothing
but a a it identifies about physical
host on which you
- satay server or associate a WebLogic
server or to do that it's used by node
manager and you also used in a cluster
cluster communication when when we look
at high availability we'll be going too
deep into that and just already showed
you how machine and node manager are
associated with each other so you go to
servers under server each server will
have a machine associated each machine
will have a node manager associated with
that and that's how these machine and
node manager are related now head on to
the next lesson when we look at security
realm which is another important topic
where you will look at how the users
security realm will have a something
called as authentication providers
authorization providers users groups
embedded LDAP servers rules all these
things we are going to look at into the
next lesson which is security lesson or
security realm I'll see you in next
lesson