so welcome back to another lesson in
this WebLogic training and in this
lesson we are going to look at data
source and Jamie's Java messaging server
but before that let me do a quick recap
on what we have covered so far so we
started with oracle weblogic 12c and 11g
where i mentioned that these are the
topics that we are going to cover so a
Giunta for this entire module including
multi-tenancy which is yet to come
then we'll go after that we'll go into
installation of WebLogic both 12c as
well as 11g so we discussed about what
is the verb logic server what are the
administration tasks for the logic
admins what the tools available for web
logic admins so things like admin
console fusion will control the logic
scripting tool restful management
resources we'll see all these incoming
modules then we looked at the logic
domain which is one of the most
important thing which is nothing but a
logical collection of servers and
associated resources for that then what
are things come consist of within a
domain in which way domain can be
deployed which is one installation
multiple domain or one domain but
multiple installations we also looked at
what is domain home what is some of the
key important files within domain home
then we looked at servers we also looked
at two different type of servers which
is had been in manage servers we also
looked at the Java Virtual Machine or
JVM we looked at what is the minimum
memory what is the maximum memory then
within admin server we said admin server
is a singleton service and managed
server is a app service or managed
server is a server on which you deploy
your applications or custom applications
we also discussed about the association
between admin and manage servers and
what are clusters and within how does
cluster communicate to each other I
mentioned that in the coming modules we
also have high availability will we look
at
unicast and multicast cluster
communication then the new concept
introduced in WebLogic 12c that's called
as dan
make clusters we're good to go deep into
these dynamic clusters or in what
components support in what don't sub
component not support will come cover
that in subsequent modules as well then
we looked at within dynamic cluster the
servers that created in dynamic cluster
is called as dynamic service which are
based on a server template so this is
what we covered in the previous lesson
now let's look at JDBC or data sources
so when WebLogic server is an
application server that hosts or deploy
application on top of that however the
data for that application goes into the
database and the way or how an
application server connects to the
database or how WebLogic connects to the
database is using JDBC that stands for
Java database connectivity now so what
you do you create a data source and how
to create a data source be able to look
in a minute and there are different
types of data sources we'll look in that
as well
so the way to connect or the the way
WebLogic server connection to a database
it uses JDBC there are different type of
data sources and one of them is generic
data source which will be used if you
have a database like single node
database of single instance database
which could be an Oracle database my my
sequel database or any other databases
you will have you will create genre data
sources then you also can create a grid
link data source and what that grid
links data source will come into picture
is when you have it Oracle database with
rack or stands for real application
cluster now if you're not familiar with
Iraq you need to understand just one
high level that it's nothing but same
database but running two instances on
two machines for high availability so
you put a grid link data source which
will connect from the Balaji to first
node and also second node and as new
node of database connects or become part
of rack cluster the generic data source
will automatically add or remove as and
when a rack database node being
added at the back end or removed so grid
link data source if you're part of
Oracle Fusion Middleware we're also
going to go deep into this grid link
data source when we look at high
availability module then there is a
multi data source which is same as
multiple versions or multiple genetic
data sources
we'll make a grid or multi data source
what will have same metadata source will
again come into picture when you have a
rank database so suppose you have two
node rack database or real application
cluster database or three node rack
database each instance of rack database
will have a generic data source and
collection of these generic data sources
will have a multi data source assume
that one pipe then going into three
different pipe or two different pipe
based on number of rack database nodes
that together will make a multi data
source we'll see that as well when we
look at high availability so these are
three different ways of did or three
different type of data sources that you
can create now multi data source and a
grid link both are for rack grid link is
a little bit more advanced feature and
depending on the WebLogic version which
you are using it you may have to pay
some extra license fee for to use that
feature however the license fee is
outside scope of this this course so but
it could be free as well the advantage
of using grid link is when the any
back-end database node gets added or
removed from a rack cluster of the
database the applica
the WebLogic server will automatically
add or remove because it's a grid link
so Gridlink have that feature
now these configurations are stored
under domain home config JDBC so entire
domain as we discussed earlier this it's
something called as a domain home all
the configurations will go inside domain
home config and JDBC folder so let's
connect to the web logic console of 12c
and see how does it look like and be
able to go and quickly create a database
if possible or and where these we'll see
also see where these files are stored on
the file system so I am on the console
here
and this is a change Center which means
if I need to make any modifications and
if my WebLogic domain is configured in a
production mode
we'll see that what is the production
mode in a minute or in subsequent
lessons but for now assume that in order
for me to make any changes in this
console I need to enable a lock which
I've already done and then I you go to
services and go to data sources and from
here from data sources you go and create
a new data source so you drop down and
say what kind of data sources you want
now because it's it well see there are
two more data services being added which
is proxy data source and UCP and we'll
be I'll be adding that as a bonus lesson
on these two additional data sources so
we let we have going to country create a
generic data source and in generic data
source you will give the name so we will
say that JDBC for example DB one and
scope again we could look at scope in
subsequent lesson in this in this module
we're Skoob feature but introduced
because multi-tenancy feature or
multi-tenancy feature introduced into NC
now jndi name will be the name used by
the application to use this database so
instead of application will not use this
name called JDBC DB one the application
if needs to access this JDBC it's going
to use this jndi name here so we will
specify some J&D a name and you specify
with what database you want to connect
and then in subsequent screens you need
to provide the database hostname port
number and configuration and other
details for connecting to the specific
database and you finish a complete
successfully and that's how you create
JDBC we'll go into these details when we
go and look at in if you're looking this
infusion will be a training then you are
going to look in and we go deep dive
into this in in the sewer module or
we'll see some of these JDBC s depending
on where you're looking will go in
detail about this ma this JDBC
now if you look at the configuration
file where these configurations are or
where with this configuration we'll go
we are it's going to go into domain home
and then config folder and inside that
config folder you will have all the
configurations of WebLogic domain will
be under domain home conflict inside
that they'll be a folder called JDBC and
that's where my Java database
configurations are this config dot XML
files the main configuration for entire
domain my gdb sees will be here and
because I don't have any JDBC or any
database connection right now in this
domain because there is no domain here
are details configured in that's why I
don't see any configuration let's
connect to another WebLogic domain or
another machine that has this JDBC and
we'll connects with that machine and see
how does it look like so I'm connecting
to another WebLogic domain and now in
that which this is a 12-11 GData
WebLogic server so our web project
console here under data sources I have
all these JDBC s so if I connect to the
putti to the backend server or let me
connect to this one of the NC you how
does it look like so I'm connecting to
Oracle access manager datasource and I
can look at connection pool will give me
information like this is my database
hostname this is my port number this is
my service name it's using using or
connecting using a user called dev
underscore om and shown where this or
what all servers WebLogic server can use
this JDBC that will be available under
targets which means this gdb C is
targeted to admin server or empathy
manager and om cluster so what you see
here this is my this is being targeted
so this JDBC can only be used by admin
server
oh Emily C manager and om cluster if my
bi server will try to connect that or
use this Jane di or this JDBC then which
using JDBC OMD this if not it won't be
able to do that because it will say hey
no debate no JDBC connection found
because this gdb C is targeted only on
selective admin and managed server and
cluster not to all servers now if we
look at the same thing for config
which in point of view so I'll connect
to another server no this is wrong so
I'm going to into this domain where my
domain are the domain that has JDBC I'll
go into same domain home config and then
JDBC so under config folder I will also
have JDBC and now if you see here each
JDBC that I have in the back end here so
each JDBC or each data source here so
they are around 17 of them
I should have 17 or so files here one
each representing a data source so now
if you are hitting any problem and you
want to know where the database is
connect or where this JDBC is connecting
to I can go to OEM deep DB JDBC and open
it and you'll tell me my hostname port
number and service name this is my
database username password is stored in
an encrypted AES algorithm base or AES
it uses AES encryption method to encrypt
the password for this schema and on the
on the the WebLogic server so that's
about weblog that's about JDBC now let's
look at one more topic before we hadn´t
to the next lesson
so JMS and Jamis is in a simple terms
nothing but Java messaging server which
is now which enables or JMS enables
applications or multiple applications or
different applications to s
synchronously communicate with each
other using messages so I have an
application one and it needs to send a
message to another application you use
JMS by s and conversely sending these
messages across each other and WebLogic
support that JMS implementation now Jim
the applications in within within
WebLogic server or JMS it can
Jamis blind or JMS server or both so
within that it can act both Jamie's
client and Jamie's server now the
application that's sending or that's
sending the message will be become a
producer and the application that
collects that message will become a
consumer within JMS client server
architecture and WebLogic supports JMS
1.1 specification so and how do you
create Jamis again you depending on
which WebLogic server you are there
might be slight differences or or slight
navigation path difference you again go
back to the WebLogic domain and here you
should have messaging and jamester what
you see here the logic domain messaging
JMS server and this little bit more as
well however if you are listening this
be able to cover in in WebLogic course
so depending on if you're listening this
in WebLogic we are going to go deep into
this JMS a little bit further if you're
listening it in Fusion Middleware
or so ah we'll go slightly when we look
at so uh store that's when we are going
to touch base again a little bit more
about JMS but this is how you go and
create JMS from here so let me do a
quick recap on this lesson just on a
quick JDBC is nothing but a way to
connect from WebLogic server to the
database intel 11g there are three ways
to connect which is a generic grid link
and multi data source into NC there are
two more which we got added which you've
solved just the earlier and we able to
cover that I'm going to add a bonus
lesson in a minute on within in this
module multi data source and griddling
are both for rack database that send for
real application cluster and the
configurations are stored in domain home
config JDBC JMS it's basically
asynchronous messaging between two
applications so this is all about JDBC
and JMS in WebLogic now head on to the
next lesson we will look at node manager
and machine and this is again one of the
important or one of the topics which we
get lot of questions especially around
the machine and node manager and how I
start my servers on
- over to the WebLogic service remotely
or from a from a web logic console so
head on to the next lesson we look at
node manager and machines in WebLogic
server I'll see you in next lesson