welcome back to this lesson on WebLogic
domain in the previous lesson we looked
at the rules and responsibilities but
let's focus on now this is one of the
most important topic which is about
WebLogic domain and so domain is nothing
but a logical collection of resources or
servers and what are the resources what
are the servers be able to cover that in
a minute but what you see on the right
hand side image is nothing but a an
initiation server call a couple of
manage servers and resources or services
and then clusters all combined together
in a logical container is called as a
WebLogic domain or a domain so a domain
will always have one and mandatory one
admin server it can have 0 to n minus
servers so it can have you can create as
many many servers as you want
I think biggest I have seen is 246 or 2
to 250 roughly on to 264 I think it
could be more I worked on maximum on
that amount so you can have 0 to n minus
servers you can have 0 to n clusters
what is admin server what is managed
server
what is cluster you are going to look
that in a minute on that particular
topic then there are resources and
services so things like machine will see
what exactly is machine in coming
lessons it can have a network channel
through which data moves it could be
potent combination of port and protocol
you can have virtual hosts will see what
exactly is virtual host it can have G DB
C Java database connectivity or JMS Java
messaging server and so on so these are
resources and services then in tab
domain configuration is stored in a file
base repository and that file based
repository is called as or the location
is under domain who config configure and
examine what is domain whom we covered
it in module 1 or previous module we
looked at what exactly is to mean so
within the domain whom there is a full
to code country and within that config
folder you have a file called config dot
XML the entire configuration of that
entire domain is stored in this file
configuration file so that's about
WebLogic domain in high level will go
deep dive into these building blocks so
what I mean by build
block or deployment or topologies what
you have is these domains can be
organized in a particular format and we
will see that what the format is and
domain will have a domain home domain
will have a servers and within servers
you will have admin and manage servers
you will have clusters you will have
machines you will have doing directory
you will have the admin console so each
domain will have its own admin console
on the project console so this is all
about a domain let's quickly cover that
in for how domain topology or how domain
can be organized so you have left hand
side you see image which you have a web
logic server software installed and then
you run a utility called config dot SH
and from that utility you created domain
which is represented by domain 1 then
you rerun that domain configured SH one
more time and say I'm creating another
domain so you might have one domain for
a development environment another domain
for a test environment third domain for
Quality Assurance or QA moment so one
single WebLogic installation but
multiple domains
that's one topology or you can have
multiple each multiple installation so
you have machine one machine to machine
three or different am talking about
machine is um a word operating system or
virtual machine or virtual machines
which are a actual servers and on these
servers you have multiple web logic
installed and each you have single
domain covering multiple machines I
repeat one more time there are multiple
web logic servers and this is called as
horizontal clustering or high
availability we'll cover that in when we
look at the high will between disaster
covey we discuss about vertical and
horizontal clustering so this is
horizontal clustering in that year of a
logic server one WebLogic server two of
logics over three on three different
machines and my domain is being used of
single domain covering three of logic
servers will see that as well when we
cover in high so these are multiple ways
in which domain can be deployed
so so this is in all about topology on
domain we look at about domain home and
lot of other things like servers and
enemy server incoming less than or the
next lesson but for now let me do a
quick recap for this lesson
would we have you have a WebLogic domain
which is nothing but a logical
collection it has one admin server
mandate Creon always only one it can
have 0 2 and manage servers it can have
0 to n clusters it have other services
or resources like Machine Network
channel virtual host Java data is
connected JMS and so on the thumb free
edition is stored in a config dot XML
file it has these components as I said
just now and you can deploy or have one
verb logic software installation and
multiple domains or multiple member
logic software installations on multiple
machines but all using with having one
WebLogic domain so these are this is a
topology you can do now and on to the
next lesson we will look at the Blodgett
domain we go a little bit deep into the
domain so I will see you in next lesson