hi guys also welcome to this another
weekly life
my name is Ethel and I'm from team K
Tony Academy and like every week every
Tuesday 3:00 p.m. GMT 8 a.m. PST 8:30
p.m. est and 4 p.m. UK time because it's
a British standard or summer time we
cover this roughly around 30 to 40
minutes session I might be doing a
little bit quicker today it's a lot of
Sun today so I will be starting in a
minute but if you're watching this video
then maybe skip a minute or two and then
I'll be starting because I'm just
catching up I was just and what we are
going to cover today is about WebLogic
server verb logic and specific are
targeted for admins ebusiness suite ab
CB s so let me go straight on to the web
to the to the slides what we going to
cover but if you like anything and if
something is not clear then make sure
you ask questions are from me so let me
go and check in my slide one second yep
it looks all fine okay so I hope you are
able to see my screen let me make it
full size let me make it bigger
oh hold on yeah so this is what we are
going to cover today let me look at the
parallely in a come on my or start this
on my page as well or sorry on my phone
as well I'm just flipping up a litte bit
so I hope you can see my screen which
says WebLogic and oracle ebusiness wait
are twelve question answer and what you
see on the right hand side on this
screen is a console sorry I forgot your
console but coming from Oracle
e-business suite are 12.2 so this is a
WebLogic admin console which is coming
from ebusiness suite our 12.2 okay hold
on let me minimize
okay so this is targeted for ab CBS
parallely I'll also connect and see on
the WebLogic console let me see if I am
connected to the VPN make sure you post
all your questions when connecting to
the VPN switcher which means I'm going
to do actual hands-on we are going to
connect and work on server and I'm going
to show you how does filesystem of
e-business suite I printer to look like
and I'm going to focus for from a from
applications or from a web logic point
of view and also if you have any
question how does this work like that
why it's working like that let me know
those questions as well those who are
attending here say hi a big hi to
everyone this is the agenda be able to
cover today so let me show you this is
all be able to cover today but before
that those who are here a he Pablo of
welcome here hey RJ hello welcome here
then we have shritha hi vamsee mukesh
okay so hi everyone make sure you post
your questions that you have but this is
what we have to begin with we'll start
with WebLogic overview very quickly then
tasks performed by admins then we are
going to there was one question being
asked in past which was about that a
oracle ebusiness with art world or two
runs web logic or is run on top of
WebLogic server and that WebLogic server
has managed servers and sometimes these
manage servers go in a warning state
i'll show you all what you mean by
warning so why do they go in that
warning state it said we're going to
look at g vm memory uses garbage
collection heap dump stack dump thread
dump what are these
how does memory look like so just to UM
little bit excited because this is
something i've never covered spatially
not even in any training so this is what
we are going to look at as well what is
a young generation what is old
generation what is a heap
what is the permanent generation how
does garbage collection look like and
some of these performance are things as
well so make sure you ask a lot of
questions you come even if you are not a
apps DBA you are going to get tons of
value web logic is used everywhere
pretty much every
so you'll get tons of value so going
back and also if you if you at any point
in time you like this session don't
forget to don't forget to share and and
leave a comment to me and tell me and
give me some little hoods so that we
have more guys joining hi I use hi
Vishal is like session started yes
absolutely we shall we have started a
hoop Emma I'm audible you can hear me
Mithu hi Mootoo welcome here and let me
know as well are you guys AB CBA's do
you have are you guys AB see behaves or
not and have you worked on WebLogic or
not so this is what we'll be able to
cover so but before we go on to hold on
yeah I think I moved forward so this is
what I'll be able to cover but earlier
in the show so I have this weekly
session so early in the show this is all
we have covered in Xero one cloud like
zero one we covered cloud service model
zero three we covered 12-point checklist
to go from DBA to cloud DBA and so on so
I'm going to move a little bit quicker
but if you want you can come back again
here and have a look at this if anything
of your interest all out plenty of
useful information in all this previous
shows everything is available on
Facebook as well also I did a Fae a
WebLogic I did a web logic live hold on
there guys so I did a Facebook life I do
not Facebook like I did a free webinar
on WebLogic Oracle WebLogic server 12c
what why and how so these questions came
from there so if you want to go and
attend that as well later go back to
ketone in academy.com ford slash web
logic 0 2 so before i start everything
let's do a quick win and shout out for
some of you guys made progress last week
so big congratulations for this is for
from Quinn Lee for migrating Oracle
e-business suite lifting or migrating
from on-premise to cloud so big big
commute relations also to acknowledge he
also did lift and shift it was a little
bit painful exercise and why it was
painful was because I think Oracle
changed something with respect to
certificates so we are going to add I am
going to a blog about it and I am going
to tell you that as well
bring congratulations to both Quinn Lee
and at least and if you have achieved
something in last one week let me know
and share it with me as well and guys
I'm extremely sorry if there's a
background noise because the day door is
open it's quite hot here the place where
I am so also if you wish to continue on
a weekly basis every Thursday we have a
newsletter there's a train going next to
my house so I'm extremely sorry guys
there's a little bit background noise
this is that give me one second I'll
just quickly come and close the door and
see if there is a background noise we'll
be using
okay I'm back now guys excuse me sorry I
hope it has improved a little bit yeah
so this is I'm saying is if you have not
yet part of our weekly newsletter you
can go and subscribe to go and write
inside ki Tony Academy comm four slash
blog and get it so let me see if there's
a guys if you are here if you're an ab
CBA or if you're working on WebLogic let
me know what you work and what
challenges you face what issues you've
faced in sooner or recently so a ji man
ab c-- be having experience on WebLogic
11g but new knowledge of art 12.1 in
WebLogic perfect so if you know WebLogic
you should be able to correlate i'm
going to show it today with respect to
oracle e-business suite how does it look
like in e-business way today so what is
WebLogic those who are new who don't
know WebLogic is nothing but an
application server and it's Java EE
Enterprise Edition compliant server it
could be high version of picked up maybe
seven but it could be eight or nine I'm
not hunter percent confident but Java EE
complained what do you do you deploy and
run you deploy run and distribute Java
applications on that so any java
application you can write you can you
run it on top of application server
which is Rob logic
now it also access other services like
databases messaging external enterprise
systems like so uh sweet or cloud or any
so you can connect from WebLogic to
other enter external service or LDAP
servers as well where is it use pretty
much every product and so if you have
not worked on WebLogic you should start
learning a web logic because whether you
work on premise or you go on cloud it's
going to be used and way why because
it's used in sua it's using OPI E which
is Oracle business intelligence and why
the reason it's being used in Oracle
access manager identity manager it's
being used in EBS at 12.2 so 12.2 uses
WebLogic earlier they used to be other
application server so tell me now what
that application server was tell me what
was the application server in a bs11 ID
and what was eleven even 12.1 let's see
who can answer those are with the ab c--
BIA background
apart from that fuse and applications
also uses the
as an underlying application server
anything that runs from the cloud in a
SAS software this service uses WebLogic
Enterprise Manager 13c uses Oh give me
one second sighs I need to close the
doors sorry for that again extremely
sorry guys um this is yeah so enter
phase manager 13 see also uses for D
behave
now what 12c so those who are coming
from 11g background in 12c WebLogic
server supports multi-tenancy so we
covered this in the free webinar which
i've covered earlier on how to how to
get out of that free 90 minute webinar
where we covered 12c multi-tenancy some
of the features like partitioning of
micro containers so leave a comment to
me or leave a comment and someone will
share at the webinar replay link if you
want so it's basically one domain so
multi-tenancy is nothing but one domain
divided into multiple parts which is
called as partitions and if you are
familiar with docker so Oracle has fully
supported now WebLogic on top of docker
containers apart so similar to web logic
the other application servers are like
IBM websphere Apache Tomcat these are
two other famous application servers so
this is all in a nutshell about WebLogic
server what are some of the common tasks
done by administrators you do install
and configure or you install the project
server you configure the WebLogic domain
what you do you deploy applications that
applications could be test again if I'm
going fast
make sure you ask question I'm going to
answer those questions at each logical
point so you deploy applications on top
of and it could be a it will always be a
java application only but you can deploy
so a based application you can deploy a
web based applications you can deploy
enterprise applications quartz which is
commercially of the shelf products like
ebusiness suite
peoplesoft Hyperion or EPM or Enterprise
Performance Management Hyperion or
Fusion Applications they all use so
these are basically example of deploying
application on top of a blodgett also
admin they migrate domain
from test dev to prod you integrate with
identity and access management system
you troubleshoot issues and be able to
look at one of the issue today which is
about performance tuning where what
happens if your managed server in
e-business 2 it goes into into a running
or wait state then we are going to or
web admins they also do monitoring
management high availability set up
these are some of the things all
WebLogic admins do ok so let me take
question and ok so I usually saying I
usually say we are facing high heap uses
and high CPU uses continuously so I
usually so we are going to cover today
first of all what is heap and and CPU
and what scenarios it happens I briefly
on a high-level overview but I need a
little bit more detail in terms of what
that application is type what does your
JVM settings are do you understand what
is heap size and permanent size we are
going to cover and hopefully that will
give you some insights on to how you
troubleshoot how you can troubleshoot
Vamsi is saying Apache server in 11 I
know Apache was a web server in 11 I and
even in 11 I it's not Apache so that's a
web server so I asked a question earlier
saying oh what is were in 12.2
e-business suite I told to my
application server listens hold on let
me go and let me take these questions
and let me swap myself afraid so I asked
some questions earlier saying ebusiness
wait well dot 2 uses WebLogic server so
what are the previous version so 11 I
it's not it's not Apache Apache is a web
server I mean it's not a patch age it's
it's a web server and web server is
witches 11g OHS it uses OHS OHS is the
web server however 11 I it doesn't use
is a Apaches an application server it's
another application server the lexing
who can answer that we shall explain
12.2 architecture and how web logic is
integrated I'm going to show that it
today we shall definitely okay greet is
saying in EBS Oh a core I'm free
things tucked red ah and do we have five
Oh a core and three application server
okay so interesting question first of
all what is what is stuck thread what is
thread dump we are going to cover that
as well finally share webinar 12c AJ I
am going to leave a comment on that
so 12c webinar I'll share that as well
thinks I use okay good
thanks welcome Naga welcome Ranjith and
there's don't forget to give me a thumbs
up or little hearts as you see something
valuable coming okay so this is the free
webinar I was talking about Katyn
academy.com WebLogic 0 - there'll be a
workbook what we covered we covered all
these things what you see on the screen
so this is all things we covered we
covered what is WebLogic common tasks
tools then why you should learn web
logic we covered 12c architecture we
covered WebLogic domain JVM deployments
dynamic so we also covered clusters and
12c introduced a new concept called a
dynamic cluster which was not there in
11g in WebLogic so dynamic cluster and
how cluster communicate each other
including multicast versus unicast we
also looked at partitioning or
multi-tenancy in that we covered what is
micro container what is partitioning
what is virtual target what is the
resource isolation I also looked at
elfin checklist to learn like an expert
and then taking it to the next table so
this is all in the webinar that I
covered earlier
ok so let's begin with first question in
that webinar was asked by vivek there
were a lot of questions I answered some
but because of time we couldn't finish
all so this is what we are going to
cover first question is managed server
an e-business suite are 12.2 comes into
warning state so before I go and answer
that lets first so this was a question
being asked I'm working in Oracle
e-business suite Perl 2.3 my question is
that our way core manage servers are
going into warning state frequently and
so this is a note I added on top of that
which is Oh a code is nothing but one of
the manage servers in a very logic
domain how many of guys who don't know
about what is WebLogic domain if there's
anyone here I'm going to explain that
what is the verb logic domain those who
are not coming from 12.2 background or
not coming from WebLogic bad known if
this only someone who knows if everyone
knows about 12 herb logics
I'm going to skip that so what his
question was oh I have increased the
Java heap size so first of all what is
the heap size how do you increase it
from one get to 2gig is increasing from
1 to giggles a solution or is it
applicable for everything but he's still
getting this error and after collecting
the garbage collection so after
collecting garbage so what is garbage
how do you collect the garbage and is it
so his he's saying after collecting the
garbage it will it was okay but I want
to resolve this issue permanently how do
we solve it okay so what would you do if
you are in a situation like that wave
will you look will you simply increase 2
from 1 to 2 get are you able to do this
is something be able to cover all set
okay
so let's first begin with ABS 12.2
architecture and those this is for
oracle ebusiness wait for apps GBS and I
think those who are not coming from a
business sweet background will also find
it useful so ebusiness suite 12.2 has
like in previous versions is a
three-tier architecture you have a
database here you have an application
tier and you have a drip tier now in
database tier what are the some of the
changes which I can tell you now from
you can install 12c virgin database
using your start CD I think it's 51 so
when you install eby's this week there
is something called a start CD and
there's a number for that start CD so by
default in previous 12.2 Datuk 4 or 5 it
used to be 11g are 2 database now when
you start with 51 CD you get great
directly 12c now the 12c database other
thing which comes in ebusiness suite
12.2 is that during install time itself
you can do rack where is in previous
versions in 11 i or a 12.1 during
install you can't configure a rack you
install first single node database with
ebusiness suite and then you migrate it
to rack so that's difference or some
changes in on the database side also
there's a new concept called addition
based redefinition introduced for for
online patching which is another new
feature introduced in our 12.2
so then the major change happened on the
application tier in application tier
Oracle introduced WebLogic prior to that
in 12.1 there was OC for J so I asked
this question earlier that in 12.1 what
was the application server and
application server was OC for J Oracle
container for Java which is a 10 G
application server and prior to to L dot
1 or it 12.0 in 11 I it used to be J
serve Java server J sir which was 99
application server of oracle application
server prior to the WebLogic server so
that's called as J serve Java server so
in 12.2 oracle introduced WebLogic
server and application T or web tier is
sorry the the client here is pretty much
more or less same there are some
additional features or additional JDK
version so J GRE and new additional
browsers being supported so quickly the
database tier is this the application
tier new introduction is the logic and
web tier or planked here also there is a
dual patching and I think I've not
covered that on so I'll skip that at
that particular point now this is all
about 12.2 architecture now in 12.2
oracle also because it's WebLogic and
WebLogic has a concept called a domain
and there's no one who said I know what
I don't know I'm not sure should I cover
this so guys I'm going to wait for a
second and tell me should I cover
WebLogic domain or not are you clear
anyone even if once a person says Oh
cover logic domain I'm going to cover
that other result skip that the blodgett
domain I'll take a strip of water and
then I'll come to that point and tell me
should I it should we do WebLogic domain
or not in the meantime let me tell you
how does it WebLogic domain look like so
I'm connecting to one of my servers and
I think it's 63-65 console so this is I
am right now logging in this is an
Oracle e-business suite and I'm
connecting to 7:01 3 which
a WebLogic admin code so I say WebLogic
and click on login and Armani WebLogic
domain so this is called as a domain if
I go in left hand side and I click on
servers and then I see there is on top
there is an admin server and this is
managed server and it's very important
this is one of the most important thing
the whole thing that you see around is a
domain and there is a admin server and
there is madness servers
there's also applications deployed and
also the connectivity to the database so
what you see here datasource
so there are two data sources one is we
have its going to the e-business suite
database and also there is a oaa this is
this doesn't come by default on this
environment we are using this
environment this environment is also
integrated with Oracle access manager so
you have a additional man data source
connecting to the database called as oae
a so let me see if there's any question
related to should I cover the project
domain or not and if I see not even a
single person asking about domain I'll
skip that and if if otherwise if there's
a question then I'll cover that in a
minute but this is all itself WebLogic
domain coming from ebusiness suite are
12.2 so in servers you might be familiar
with in 11i as well as in 12c or sorry
in our 12.0 and 12.1 you have Oh a core
so you used to have OC 4 0 a code if you
are 12.1 if you're 11 I there's already
an OE core J sub similar to that here Oh
a core here also but it said a managed
server this is this is Oracle
application Fusion Middleware oae again
that doesn't come by default that comes
very empty this is my access gate Oracle
application ebusiness suite access gate
so oaa this is for EP om integration and
these are forms let me see and take any
questions if you guys have ok so I
should saying cover it at all please
cover and jeath we shall definitely okay
so let me cover very quickly what is
WebLogic domain it's nothing but logical
collection of all the resources clubbed
together so what I mean by the sources
is servers
all machines deployment is nothing but
web applicants or application deployment
or jar file deployment these deployments
also JDBC so these are applications so
if you see here there's a web
application called cat this is another
web application called DMS so collection
of all this is so logical collection of
all this is a web logic domain and
domain this is a two type of servers
admin server in a managed server and
it's always one and only one admin
server and multiple manage servers so
that's what we saw here and you will
always have once admin server in a
domain when you create and you can have
zero or n manage servers so this is what
you we see here now on these manage
server so admin server you deploy
something called as applications or
resources which are nothing but war web
archive er enterprise archives are job
archive JDBC Java Java database
connectivity JMS Java messaging server
and each server has its own JVM Java
Virtual Machine what I mean by that is
so forms will have a OC for oh sorry JVM
this boy code will have a JVM this will
have a JVM this will you have a JVM as
long it's running and JVM is nothing but
a java virtual machine which is what
which is nothing but it executes your
Java class file on a microprocessor so
developers will write a Java Java file
they will compile that it will become
class file and those class file will be
combined them into a jar file
these are deployed in the server and
when you sum run these these Java files
are are executed bytecodes on the JVM so
how does GBM look like or how do you
know of it kind of a JVM we have let's
go and connect on to the server so I'm
connecting to one of EB a servers behind
putty so this is how you can see what is
the JVM running so I'm connecting at
Appl MGR which is my application tier
user and I'm going to show you how does
Geum look like give it a few minutes
guys
okay give me a feedback that are you
learning it is it making sense or not
and why it's not slow okay
okay while it connects maybe maybe
because it's waiting for your little
likes and the minute you give hurts and
likes and thumbs up it might come okay
white slow new session
EBS load open okay I don't know why it's
not working but this is this is inactive
or at a we are we are here now so PS UX
and pipe so all you need to do is if you
do want to find the JVM you say PSU
x-pipe and grep for grep - I and Java
so when you say grep - I Java so each of
these processes is a JVM so what do you
see here this is one JVM what you see
here it's running Java or JDK from here
this is the name of the JVM which is OFM
so earlier we saw this there is a OFM
but important and interesting fact or
interesting thing is what is this here
this is the key lot of you guys hit
these problems which is palm-sized 128 m
max palm-sized what 3384 XM s 1 0 - 4 XM
x 1 0 - 4 so tell me what is palm-sized
what is difference between XM x s and
pump size what are the pump size and XM
s denotes what I should sing definitely
I feel I'm learning a lot great thank
you very much so tell me guys leave a
comment and tell me and if you don't
know just say I don't know and and
that's why I can go in detail about if
you don't know about this so this is and
this is all your cleaning parameters
this is where the maximum tuning will
happen around JVM or Java Virtual
Machine so going back to this is the
manage servers which you see now I'm
going to also tell you how does it look
like or file system look like very
quickly so I go on to EBS apps and right
now you this a dual file system - I am
setting it environment variable to say
source the run edition
again I'm not over what is a patchy
addiction or effects file edition but
there is a Fusion Middleware home in
e-business suite so I'm right now in
Fusion Middleware home and inside that
Fusion Middleware home I have my
WebLogic server this is my verb logic
home this is my actual TP or web server
home this is my under user projects I
have my domain this is my web gate home
if you installer and ticket with
identity and access management system
this is a common home so I'm going to go
into the user projects and inside that
domains and this is my domain name which
is eeap's abs underscore domain
underscore sid and incite that i have
been this is where my starts top of this
domain are going to be this is where my
servers are going to be so if I go under
servers folder and this is where my
admin server domain and these servers
are if I go back under config folder and
this is where the entire configuration
or WebLogic configuration will be under
here WebLogic config ok hold on VI
WebLogic dot XML
oh sorry config dot XML is my mistake so
it will be config dot XML so how you
know where is my admin server port you
go and search for look for this admin
server here and it's saying my machine
is this my listen 4701 3 it's listening
on address 1705 a cloud
Cayden academy.com like so I need to
just this and that's why you see this
I'm going directly by IP and this is the
port number seven zero one three four
slash console here ok so let's move on
now back to slide so this is about JVM
I've told you about WebLogic
configuration that where does WebLogic
configuration you set your environment
variable or an Edition go to another
environment variable or going directly
to do mean you go to EBS domain home
countries then you open config not XML
we'll file you will see file like admin
server look for admin server and listen
address and listen port number this is
the WebLogic domain I showed you earlier
this is how it look like this is the JVM
I told you earlier there is a XMS X MX
maximum size and other variable point
things on JVM so now comes the real crux
which is oh how this memory is being
used so whatever we saw in in earlier
this is JVM that you see here and we are
going to discuss next is important thing
this is where you need to learn so JVM
is divided in two or memory within the
JVM is divided into multiple parts and
two broad parts which is called as heap
and heap is nothing but collection of
young generation and old generation ways
another one is permanent germination
which is for other purpose and we'll
cover that in a minute what these are if
you look at the below diagram below that
younger generation is further divided
into three parts called Eden s 0 which
is survivor 0 and survivor 1 and things
as name suggests if and we'll cover that
in a minute as well so there are two
main areas one is called as permanent
generation which is used by JVM so JVM
internally uses a metadata and some
files so permanent generation is
reserved for that so if you have lot of
program if you have a big memory big
application you may also need to tweak
the perm size or maximum size as well
but this is permanent this is not where
your objects live this is not very of
program object lives this is the program
which is reserved by JVM and this is
where the permanent space or metadata of
Java classes being exist heap is
actually the area which is young plus
all generate old generation and this is
where the objects which your program
uses or the business logic uses or
ebusiness suite uses or any custom
application uses they need to they need
a space they use it from heap which is
young plus old generation making sense
so so collection of XML
Plus or so XMS is the Eden plus survival
zero propels survival one and and
tenured all this collection what you see
here from here XMS this is the area so
what you saw on earlier in one of the
diagrams of one of the screenshots here
or let me go back XMS yeah so this so
this means that your heap will begin
with 1 gig of memory and this is the
area which is here then it can grow up
to 1 0 to 4 it can grow up to so the in
disk in our case that means these two
areas are saying my minimum and maximum
are same for heap
similarly palm-sized this is here so my
palm size it started with 128 MB I can
grow up to 384 MB so now when you resize
this permanent jump pummelled generation
size and if you resize it quite often
it's an expensive affair it takes a lot
of time to resize or it impacts your
performance so if you have a bigger
application if you have a application
which is memory hungry like some
applications within e-business suite
it's always good practice to keep pump
size same as maximum size so that your
CPU or your JVM doesn't spend time in
changing these spaces also as I said
young generation is further divided into
two parts and in answer to server as
five spaces so what happens when a new
object so when when you when you access
something or when your application
access something and they need a space
or they need to bring some data from in
the code from the database or some other
place into the memory of the GBM the
data first comes or that those object
comes into the Aden area and over a
period of time then something happens
and what that something is called as
garbage collection which I'm going to
cover that in a minute
so then the Aden space is full or at a
particular regular interval there is
program called garbage collection and
when the garbage collection is
then our scenarios in which garbage
collection in Iran is when there's not
enough space and JVM needs memory to do
more code so garbage collection is run
so let's look at garbage collection what
is garbage collection guys am I making
sense just give me a thumbs up or thumbs
down or let me know and give me a little
hearts as well is it making sense what
is garbage collection what is the
previous slide that we covered here I'll
take a sip of water
okay let me take hi MA Jean welcome here
thank you very much guys for these
little hearts thank you very much and
these means a lot to me this inspired me
to do a more and more so and also if you
like this don't forget to share with
your colleagues and friends as well I
used to sing don't know about palm-sized
and XM s don't worry we'll go back to
this slide one more time I don't know
and palm-sized is where the WebLogic
class package are loaded absolutely
unfamiliar with optimal tuning for the
different servers in JVM and you so this
is where palm-sized is where you have
the metadata of the class metadata of
the class
not exactly the yeah okay so coming back
to garbage collection and this is very
important this is where a lot of tuning
especially with the memory hungry
application so garbage collection is
nothing but process of looking at
objects in heap and we told you earlier
what is heap heap was nothing but old
generation and new generation or young
generation in the old generation area so
process of looking at the heap objecting
here and deleting the unused one so if
any spit any object is no more you in
use then deleted to clear some space and
there are two type of GCS or garbage
collection we call some one is called as
- GC and second is called as major GC
now when a young generation fills up a
minor GC is kicked in so I told you
earlier what is young generation the
area space you see on the left hand side
which is new sighs sorry the area which
is some part of of the heap so when that
fills up then minor GC kicks in and what
happens when minor thing - GC kicks in
the application threads stop application
Hanks or halts comes to a halt for that
GC to finish so we call it stop the
world event it stops everything so
imagine you are in middle of if
application is running doing something
and the minor G C comes application will
come to a halt but your
objective should be to keep that GC of
finish as quickly as possible then
there's a another one which is major GC
which cleans up unused objects in the
old generation area
so major GC also like young like minor
GC stop applications and it basically
also stops applications so objective
should be to minimize that time
application works or spends on running a
major GC and ideally try to be keep it
between three to five seconds yeah
so now GC can be of type serial parallel
CMS and g1 I'm not going to go into
detail here but if you want further
detail leave a comment I'm going to give
you the references on where you can read
further again we cover in one of the
other performance tuning our training on
for ab CBS as well as on WebLogic these
these go in detail ok so what now if you
are working on a performance issue what
your objective should be to you the time
spend in GC to be at least or minimum or
less than 5% of execution type of the
full JVM also the Jeep JVM heap size did
determine so the heap size of the JVM
which is collection of young and old
generation that determines how long and
how often the GC should run also if
there is a large heap full GC is going
to be slower but it's going to be less
frequent so the size if you if you make
it too big it it's going to be slower
the GC is going to take longer but it it
will be less frequent so what happens if
GC is full and after sorry if the JVM
heap is full and even even after running
garbage collection it can't find any
space and all the objects aren't in use
that's when you get errors like
java.lang out of memory error you might
have seen a lot of these Java lying out
of memory errors as well then if you
want to see how much time is being spent
by the application
or the JVM in order for the GC or during
the GC time then you can meet there's an
option in when you start the GBM so this
like this here you put one more option
here in one of the environment variables
and you put - verbose GC to find out how
much time is being spent on GC so this
is how you do so this is just a nutshell
about just to do a quick recap before I
take one or two questions and we'll move
on so JVM there are two main areas palm
gen and heap and heap is young plus old
generation there's a within young
generation this is a Eden and two
survivors so basically the objects move
from one survivor to another survival
before and still ye being used then they
go to the old generation as the cleanup
words garbage collection process of
cleaning up the unused objects there are
two type minor and major and objective
should be to minimize the JVM time spent
in in running the GC and else otherwise
you might get out of memory errors so
before we move on to the next one let's
look at one or two questions and then
I'll move on to are you guys
understanding learning getting value on
that let me see okay good thanks give me
a little Hertz and tell me you're
enjoying this session or not I can see a
lot of you guys here when GC runs user
will be terminated from application no
user will not be terminated user will
continue it just they might see some
short a certain performance hits in
terms of it might be it might wait for a
few seconds or you might see or
everything frozen
that's how but user will never be
terminated or user will not terminate
from here okay let's move on so what is
so what is heap dump you will hear that
word coming again and again the guys are
saying oh can you do the heap dump so
heap dump is nothing but process of
dumping the entire memory allocation
within a JVM whatever is going on right
now with the JVM you dump that that's
called as heap dump so you are going to
do heap dump analysis mainly when you
get out of memory errors or memory leak
in the application
how you're going to identify whether the
same memory leak or if it's out of
memory issue you will see in the log
file is out of memory or if you increase
the memory and again and again you are
seeing out of memory so let's suppose
you have increased from one get two to
being and you still get out of memory
error that means hey that means there is
a memory leak and so you dump that heap
dump and it'll tell you or it will give
you a hint whether there's a memory leak
or not
so heap dump is different from thread
dump again another important thing don't
makes heap dump is for memory thread
dump is for thread and we'll see that in
a minute so how you can take the heap
dump
there are various parameters and one of
the parameter you can add it in with in
GBM start up and you say xxxx heap dump
on out of memory and then you say heap
dump path and you specify where should
it generate that file so you put that
and so you can do it so on on the
startup in an environment variable so
when it does and any out of memory
happens the heap dump will be
automatically on the time or you can use
an application like third party or
external part or tool like J map or also
there's a another one which is Jake on
so these are gray or graphical user
interface so once it's dump is done you
need to read it and how you route read
again there are tools like Eclipse
memory analyzer or J hat or IBM or IBM
heap analyzer again good point in
e-business suite if you're hitting
problem like ebusiness suite because
it's commercially of the self
application you don't need to worry
about it you give it to a business suite
or the product support team
they will look out look it for you
however if you develop your custom
application on top of ebusiness suite
then you might have to look at this
application again give it to the
developer they might they will give you
a hint
or they will tell you
okay then there is a next one as I said
is javis tech trees and threat dump
again thread dump is different from a
stack trace and also thread up is
different from heap dump so state trees
is it's nothing but a user-friendly
snapshot of threads which monitors and
including monitors in JVM so JVM has
threads and monitors so the snapshot of
of that at any given point in time is
called a stack trace it helps in
troubleshooting hanging or spinning java
applications so some of you guys were
saying oh my application hangs or taking
longer than it should or sometimes we
notice that performance issue or my J my
JVM or my processes reach 200% CPU so in
that case you should run Java stack
trace similarly sometimes you will get a
warning state in application says and
this tie back to the error everything we
are discussing about is the error from
the webinar that we discussed at the
start so what happens there's a thread
dump so if there are stuck threads then
you might want to do read dump which is
nothing but snapshot of all the threads
in the application at that point now
stack trip sorry it's a typo it's a
stack trace will not show memory
distribution for memory if you're in
memory you need to go back to the heap
dump if you want ten dump or stack trace
then you pick it here now again how do
you create a stack trace you run you
simply say kill as you signal quit
signal to the JVM so you need to find
out what is the JVM how do you find out
GBM again you do psu X and now if you
see here on this here screen update PSU
X and grab for Java and I found out
let's suppose I need to find out J
process ID for JV of form server I'll
simply do that and six six four four is
to the process ID so once I know the
process ID I'll simply is a kill - three
and process ID and there are one or two
different type of kill as well you can
even do that now output will be written
in ASCII format and simply use any
format like editor or
VI or notepad to open that stake trace
or third um okay so just to do a quick
recap on what we looked at so we said
there is a heap dump which is the dump
of memory there is a set dump which is a
dump of thread at that point in JVM
stack trace which is a snapshot of
threads as well as monitors in JVM so
coming back to the main question
oh I'm hitting this problem how should I
troubleshoot so now first of all if
there's a warning you need to look into
the application log file so that warning
could be for multiple reasons so make
sure you look at the managed server log
file
now first you to find out and where
these log files will be visible give me
one second guys so let me swap my screen
and let me take one any question is
there's no question no oh okay so there
is a question from Mozilla saying my
report server is hanging very often
often so first of all there are some
magic if you are your report server is
hanging first of all which version of
e-business suite you are working on also
check that are there any performance
patches available because Oracle
e-business suite team gives you a
performance patches are quite regularly
so make sure you have those performance
patches or not but if you tell a little
bit more detail in terms of which
ebusiness suite version it is what path
sets you have we should be able to add a
little bit or give a little bit more
value or such on my Oracle support there
are performance patches of way available
for reports which should not is saying
some of us missed the session can we
have the presentation public so that we
can download and go through so don't
worry you watch the replay so replay
will be available on the same page which
is Katun academy.com first eby's flour
0eb is sorry cloud-like 13k toning
academy.com ford slash cloud-like 13
which not go back to that and and ask
again so let me hold on let me see the
whatever stock yeah so let me swap okay
so this is what I was talking about
right now state is running shutdown
running running running so I have 4 J 5
J
I'm running and one is down and here if
there's any problem you will see warning
here so he will see his status as a
warning and if you're in a situation
like that look at make a note of which
application it is and then look at sorry
which man is over is this oayk or here
so the ones will you know the
application then you go to the oayk or
managed server log file so where are
those log files we told you that it will
be under domain home so right now we
this is my domain home inside inside
that I'll go to servers an inside server
I'll go to the appropriate server in
which where I'm hitting this performance
problem or the warning so I'll go to way
code and then logs and within logs do LS
- ltr' and this should be out file and
this should be a diagnostic file so
these are the two files you should focus
out and diagnostic so in out file most
probably it will be in if it's out of
memory it will be in out file output
file and right now I don't think I'm
hitting any problem no there's no error
there's no memory error so otherwise you
will get the warning here this is what
you will see like so the warning could
be for multiple reasons and you can't
predict by telling oh I'm getting a
warning it could be for multiple reasons
so this question was asked by forgot
name of the gentleman in the webinar so
it could be JDBC connection issues so
have a look at so what is JDBC I told
you earlier that okay here this
application needs to talk to the
database or WebLogic needs to talk to
the database and that database
connectivity is is this JDBC connection
issue one so if you see error like Oh
pool connection Oracle GBPC driver if
you see something like that that means
it's a JDBC issue or you can see stuck
thread so other application will tell
here stuck threads so you will see the
message as stuck thread so you click or
you do the thread dump and thread dump
you will you see which where exactly the
stuck thread is waiting on again there
are lot of known issues with respect to
e business suite so make sure you have
all the performance patches applicable
on that so this is this was
one question and as I said if you want
to watch all other questions which have
answered in the webinar if you have to
go through the WebLogic 12c
multi-tenancy micro container partitions
again the replays available on Titan
Academy Comfort / web-browsing 0 - again
we are not going to keep this replay for
long and so I'm going to take few more
one more questions and see if there's
any question but there were a lot of
other questions being asked and I think
looking at the time I didn't expect that
it's going to take that too long so I'll
I probably should view this remaining
questions in our private Facebook group
and I will tell you what that group is
will be discussed there so remaining
questions I'm going to take it in
private Facebook group so Dave jeath and
green that asks the same question what
if host one hosting the admin server
crashes so I'll quickly tell you that
admin server is a singleton service
which can run only on one node so what
if that node goes down how do we
failover how do the admin server is
going to work what what is going to
happen with remaining manage servers
what will happen to the classified min
server goes down and we also looked at
the clustering in the webinar which is
horizontal versus vertical clustering
then there was a concept we discussed
about virtual IP and where is it used
what should I be any in admin server
also how does admin server
high-availability works there's also a
question from vedanta bout certification
when is there a certification for web
logic or not so there are certification
I'm going to tell a little bit more in
detail there's a question from Syed
Sahib sameen can I configure a load
balancer between the WebLogic and HTTP
server sorry WebLogic and end-user so
this is the architecture which said you
have users going from the firewall to
the load balancer to the web server to
the WebLogic
so this is the on right hand side yes
few users load balancer HTTP server and
web logic so the question was is that
Oracle HTTP server or OTD also we
discussed in the webinar is that
mandatory so that question again I'm
going to pick that also if you're
putting load balancer what is Oracle's
recommendations for these load balancers
so as I said go and have a look at it
WebLogic zero two and salumi Dean also
how to connect to the JDBC or data
sources what is Gridlink what is multi
data source so this is also supposed to
cover which is how do you connect to the
database what the JDBC sees so I'm going
to discuss this all this in this
community which is catered in
academy.com /join FB if you're not part
of this I would highly recommend you to
be part of this be part of this
community I'm going to cover that apart
from that we also have a worship group
it's what we have a separate whatsapp
group for paid members this is for free
members if you want to discuss and
communicate Kate Undine academy.com
/what self also if you're a DBA I would
love you to be if you're a DBA or
interested in cloud either DBA or cloud
we are doing a free live webinar on this
Saturday which is on 12th where 12th of
May we were able to cover everything
like why you learn cloud what is cloud
computing what is the cloud service
models SAS pass idlest what are the
cloud deployment models then be able to
look at how do you build your first
Oracle database on cloud not in
infrastructure and service but in plate
formatted service how do can you create
it under 10 minutes or so or everything
up and running within 30 minutes then 12
point checklist to go from complete
beginner to expert if you're a DBA
you'll get tons of value if you're not a
DBA you will still learn but focused on
cloud so the URL is ketone academy.com
forward slash cloud zero - so with that
as I said go and make sure you become
part of this community and let me take
few questions if there's any question if
I need to or if there's any but I think
I've covered all the questions let me
know if you found value in this webinar
so if you found okay I'm just telling to
my wife are my kids I'm just about to
finish this webinar so let me know if
you have any questions and and give me a
thumbs up or did you find value should
we continue doing that what should be
the next topic we should do so next week
I'm planning to do either on ebusiness
suite or or on plow
networking last time I asked this
question there were a lot of questions
came about cloud networking what is
virtual cloud network what is SSH
connection what is fast connect what is
Reuters what is gateway what is class
IPs what is a so if you're interested in
that let me know thank you very much for
these Hertz means a lot to me and don't
forget to share with your friends and
colleagues every Tuesday we cover how to
recover basically a topic in Oracle and
so make sure you ask and and you tell it
tell it to others with that ok let me
take thank you each one of you for being
here and spending some time with me and
so next week either I'm going to wait
for comments either were able to cover
networking in cloud or which is Oracle
cloud infrastructure so things like or I
might cover the Blodgett or I might
cover DVR ebusiness suite or ab CB o so
AJ saying I'm eagerly waiting for that
network session so AJ of great yeah so
networking one and the lot of questions
come coming on networking as well so
with probably most probably chances are
networking will be lot of value in that
I learned a lot in last 3-4 weeks about
networking in order to prepare for that
webinar or networking sessions or things
like subnet things like internet gateway
a dynamic routing gateway VPN fast
connect virtual cloud network and so on
thank you guys are with that thanks for
more - and with that ba bye take care
and as I said don't forget to share it
with your friends and colleagues and be
part of that group which is Facebook
group we are going to take up follow up
questions related to this um Kay tuning
academy.com /join FB I'll see you next
week same time bye for now