hi everyone again so in the previous
video I covered theory part on what is
Oracle HTTP server and WebLogic
integration look like and we looked at
modern score WL underscore OHS in this
video I'm going to cover or do a
hands-on on witches WebLogic server
integration so let's jump on to the
server first I'm going to first look at
the browser on where I'll be accessing
an Oracle HTTP server page and WebLogic
server URL and then we'll configure on
the server integration between OHS and
web logic and then finally access those
configuration on the browser so let's
jump on to the server now so if you look
at the server i'm currently connecting
to the browser and i'm trying to access
first the oracle HTTP server page which
is IM dot k 21 technologies comm forward
slash seven seven seven seven this is
where my Oracle HTTP server is running
so this is showing that this an Oracle
HTTP server page and if I type forward
slash console since there is nothing
configured it's saying or there's no
forward slash console configured I'm
getting the requested URL not found so
if I look at the server right now so
because I'm accessing forceless console
the entry should come into the access
log so let's look at in my server the
diagnostic log so if I go to the
diagnostics and then logs and then OHS
which is one so we covered in one of our
previous videos the log file and
configuration file so if I'm doing tale
minus F on access log so X is log is the
file in which any request that goes to
the Oracle HTTP server are recorded so
the location is this is my Oracle
instance then you have Diagnostics
logs OHS and OHS one so I'm doing tail -
F and access log and where I cried
accessing console so let's put few
enters here and then forwards less
console and I get console so it says
it's coming from this IP this is my
client IP this is the date on which I
have attempted this the method of
accessing this page is get so there's a
get and post and head so it's a get
forward slash console and 404 is the
HTTP code which is page not found and
190 is the I think it's a byte or size
so this page is not found now I start
another one and then this time I type
but seven thousand one which is my
WebLogic console that's where my
WebLogic console is running and I can
access this console next I'm going to do
is I'm going to configure that so that
this forms less console from my HTTP
server is also accessible so that I
don't have to go to seven thousand one
port or the WebLogic server so in order
to achieve that I'll first go to my
configuration folder where my
configurations are for mod WL OHS that's
under Oracle instance which is this
folder and then config and then OHS
which is one and this is the file which
I'm going to modify so I'll take a
backup of this file mod WL underscore
witch's sorry this mod underscore WL OHS
underscore conf underscore re and I'll
do open up more WL which is conf and I
will say uncomment this and uncomment
this and here I am going to change the
host team my host name where WebLogic is
running is I am dot k21
technologies dot-com and the port number
is 7,001 I'll come in from here this
forward slash remove this and I'll leave
path cream or so I'll say opium in CTL
stop all to stop my Oracle HTTP server
and I'll do then do Oracle opium in CTL
start all so in order for this
configuration to take into effect I need
to restart my Oracle HTTP server so that
the updated mod WOL OHS comes into
effect ok so that didn't work and I
think I know the reason I should have
changed here instead of WebLogic should
have been console so the reason is I did
a typo here so to be console let's stop
or restart the Oracle HTTP server again
so I'm starting the server again so now
restarted the Oracle HTTP server with
the correct entry and now let's look at
the Oracle so now if you see it's seven
seven seven seven forward slash console
and I'm still able to access the same
console for WebLogic through Oracle HTTP
server so I'll enter now username
WebLogic and password as welcome one or
the password that is for the blodge ik
and I can access this I am dot K 21
technologies comm four slash console now
this is seven seven seven seven which is
the Oracle HTTP listener port and this
is what it's configured now now some
applications expect you to have the
plug-in enabled and this is that
configuration which I earlier showed
into the video so you go to the advanced
and you say WebLogic plug-in enabled so
this parameter specifies of the weather
server uses WL proxy client IP header
which is recommended if server instance
will receive requests from plug c plugin
yeah so this is a recommended setting
sometime allah console will work but
there are a lot of a plane
occasions which don't work if you don't
have this plug-in selected so you select
the plug-in for on to the server in our
case we have enabled on admin server but
you go and change it on the respective
server to which your forwarding request
from Oracle HTTP server so let's suppose
I'm configuring to so I inflow from my
study B server I'll go to the sewer
manage server under advanced and I'll
enable this HTTP or plug-in which is
this WebLogic plug-in enable this so
this completes the hand-sewn on how to
configure Oracle HTTP server as a
reverse proxy for application or for
WebLogic server and that we are going to
use quite actively in our Oracle Fusion
Middleware so just to recap on in this
video we looked at how to configure
Oracle HTTP server as a reverse proxy
for WebLogic server where we modified
mod underscore WL underscore OHS conf to
include or forward any request coming to
forward slash console to HTTP server to
the Oracle WebLogic server in the next
video we're going to look at how the
same configuration is configured on
Oracle EBS 12.2 so hit on to the next
video to look at the configuration
setting in Oracle EBS 12.2 for Oracle
HTTP server and how these configurations
are pointing applications deployed on
Oracle WebLogic domain for EBS 12.2
you