hi everyone my name is Otto Kumar and in
this section we are going to look at
question answer related to this module
so the first question which is from saya
is related to Oracle Fusion Middleware
homes and the question is what is
coherence home so if you have not looked
at the various homes in Oracle Fusion
Middleware have a look at that first in
that video there I covered various homes
like WebLogic home Java home Oracle home
domain and instance home so similar to
those homes oracle coherence home is the
top-level directory under which
coherence related executables are stored
or the software is stored so coherence
is used in Oracle Fusion Middleware as a
caching software so it holds the data
cache and it also is being used in some
of the Oracle Fusion Middleware product
for clustering like Oracle access
manager Oracle so us wait so when you
install Oracle Fusion Middleware use
install Oracle WebLogic installer with
coherence let me take you to the server
while installing WebLogic and when
you're installing WebLogic you will get
an option to install coherence and you
select installer of WebLogic with
coherence so let's go on to the server
so if you look at now I am on server and
I'm starting the installation of AB
logic server using Java
- jar WLS 10:36 generic jar this is also
covered in our web logic module where we
say installation of AB logic so hit
enter and on one of the screen you will
notice that it's prompting for coherence
home so if you notice here it says
choose install type and I have a typical
where I have WebLogic server and oracle
coherence so since I have
used an installer WebLogic installer
that has both WebLogic as well as oracle
coherence that's why I'm getting this
option so in Oracle Fusion Middleware
products for installing components like
sewer OB ie WebCenter
identity and access management software
like Oracle access manager or Identity
Manager you should use coherence so when
you select this it is going to create a
directory so let me cancel this I
already have an installation which I'm
going to show you so go to you 0 1 app
Oracle fmw underscore sewer and inside
that I have this directory coherence
underscore 3.7 so this is my coherence
home so the Goron's home is till here
which is you 0 1 app Oracle fmw
underscore so our coherence underscore
3.7 so the oracle coherence says top
level directory in which coherence
software is configured installed and
configured in your Oracle Fusion
Middleware environment
thanks a it for asking this question